Kids! Breakfast!
Kids?
- Phil, would you get them?
- Yeah. Just a sec.
Kids!
- That is so...
- Okay.
Kids?! Get down here!
Why are you guys yelling at us
when we're way upstairs?
- Just text me.
- That's not gonna happen.
- And you're not wearing that outfit.
- What's wrong with it?
Honey, do you have anything
to say to your daughter about her skirt?
Sorry.
That looks really cute, sweetheart.
It's way too short. People know you're
a girl. You don't need to prove it.
Luke got his head stuck
in the banister again.
I got it.
- Where's the baby oil?
- It's in our bedside tab...
I don't know. Find it.
Come on!
I was... out of control growing up.
There. You know, I said it.
I just don't want my kids
to make the same bad mistakes I made.
If Haley never wakes up
on a beach in Florida half-naked,
I've done my job.
Our job.
Right.
I've done our job.
Vamos, Manny! Kick it! Kick it!
Don't let him... Kick it!
Manny, go.
He tripped him, Jay!
Where's the penalty?
Gloria, they're 0-6.
Let's take it down a notch.
We're very different.
Jay's from the city.
He has a big business.
I come from a small village,
very poor but very, very beautiful.
It's the number-one village
in all Colombia for all the...
- What's the word?
- Murders.
Yes, the murders.
Manny, stop him!
You can do it!
Damn it, Manny!
Come on, coach!
You got to take that kid out!
You want to take him out?
How about I take you out?
Honey, honey.
Why don't you worry about your son?
He spend the first half
with his hand in his pants!
I've wanted to tell her off
for the last six weeks.
I'm Josh. Ryan's dad.
Hi. I'm Gloria Pritchett,
Manny's mother.
- And this must be your dad.
- Her dad?
That's funny.
Actually, no, I'm her husband.
Don't be fooled by the...
Give me a second here.
Who's a good girl?
Who's that?
She's adorable!
Hi, precious.
We just adopted her from Vietnam,
and we're bringing her home
for the first time, huh?
She's an angel.
You and your wife must be thrilled.
Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry.
Daddy needed snacks.
So...
What are we talking about?
We have been together for...
God, five... Five years now?
We decided we really wanted
to have a baby.
So we had initially asked one of our
lesbian friends to be a surrogate.
Then we figured,
they're already mean enough.
Can you imagine one of them pregnant?
No, thank you. Ick.
You saw that, right?
Everybody fawning over Lily,
and then you walk on,
and suddenly it's all, "Oh, Skymall.
I got to buy a motorized tie rack."
- All right, I'm gonna give the speech.
- You are not giving the speech.
We are gonna be stuck with these people
for the next 5 hours.
You're right, I'm sorry.
Look at that baby
with those cream puffs.
Excuse me, but this baby would have
grown up in a crowded orphanage
if it wasn't for us "cream puffs."
And you know what?
To all of you who judge, hear this.
Love knows no race, creed...
Or gender.
And shame on you...
You small-minded, ignorant few...
What?
She's got the cream puffs.
We would like to pay
for everyone's headsets.
Buddy, why do you keep
getting stuck like this?
I thought I could get out this time.
I'm just gonna say it.
He needs to be checked
by a specialist.
There!
Be free, Excalibur.
- I'm having a friend over today.
- Who?
You don't know him.
"Him"? "Him"?
A boy.
You gonna kiss him?
- Shut up!
- Easy. Easy.
Luke, Alex, why don't you
take it outside, okay?
- And do what?
- Fight in the sun, for a nice change.
- I'm kidding.
- Who's the boy?
His name is Dylan.
I might as well
tell him not to come,
because you are just
going to embarrass me again.
Hang on a second. You're 15,
it's the 1st time you've had a boy over.
I'm bound to be a little surprised,
- but I'm not gonna embarrass you.
- I better go charge the camcorder.
I'm kidding! Come on!
Who are you talking to?
I'm the cool dad. That's my thing.
I'm hip. I surf the web. I text.
"L.O.L." -- "Laugh out loud."
"O.M.G." -- "Oh, my God."
"W.T.F." -- "Why the face?"
I know all the dances
to "High School Musical." So...
- Mom! Dad!
- What happened?
- Luke just shot me!
- I didn't mean to!
Are you okay?
No! The little bitch shot me!
Language!
They're only plastic BBs.
It was an accident.
What did I tell you would happen
if you got him a gun? Deal with this.
Buddy, uncool.
That's it?
The agreement was that if he shoots
someone, you shoot him.
We were serious about that?
We were, and now
you have to follow through.
- I'm so sorry!
- Liar.
- Go.
- He's got a birthday party.
What's more important here, Dad?
Shoot him afterwards.
He'll be home at 2:00.
- I can't. I'm showing a house at 2:00.
- What about 3:00?
He's got a soccer game at 3:00,
and then...
We got to leave
for that dinner thing at 5:00.
- 4:15. You could shoot him at 4:15.
- I guess that works for me.
"Shoot Luke."
Sorry, dude.
It's on the calendar.
Come on.
I'm quitting soccer.
It is a game for children.
You're not quitting.
You would have stopped that goal if you
weren't staring at that little girl.
She is not a girl. She is a woman.
Gloria, that blow-up with the other mom,
why do you have to do things like that?
If somebody says something
about my family...
I'm just saying, you could take it
down here a little bit, that's all.
'Cause that's where you live, downhere.
But I live uphere!
You don't have to be so emotional
all the time. That's all I'm saying.
- Manny, you're with me on this, right?
- I wanna tell Brenda I love her.
- Oh, for God's sakes.
- Manny, she's 16.
Oh, it's okay for you
to take an older lover?
Watch it!
I want to go
to the mall where she works.
But first I need to get
my white shirt, the silk one.
- That's what you really want to do?
- Seriously, not to be the evil stepdad,
but if you put on a puffy white shirt
and declare your love for a 16-year-old,
you're gonna be swinging from the
flagpole in your puffy white underpants.
Stop the car!
Where are you going?
You see?
You hurt his feelings.
Well, if it toughens him up
little bit, then...
Aw, geez.
He's picking flowers.
Manny's very passionate,
just like his father.
My first husband,
he's very handsome but too crazy.
It seemed like all we did
was fight and make love,
fight and make love,
fight and make love.
One time, I'm not kidding you,
we fell out the window together.
Which one were you doing?
I'm hearing this for the first time.
This doesn't worry you?
She barely slept on the plane,
and she's still wide awake.
Stop worrying!
Cam, that orphanage was all women.
Maybe she can't fall asleep
unless she feels a woman's shape.
- I guess that's possible.
- So, here.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
I've gained a few extra pounds
while we were expecting the baby,
which has been very difficult.
But, apparently, your body does
a nesting, very maternal, primal thing
where it retains nutrients.
Some sort of
molecular physiology thing.
But that's science.
You can't... You can't fight it.
So...
- I'm not saying anything.
- You're saying everything.
Count to three.
- Oh, my God. Do you love it?
- Yes. I...
What the hell is that?
I had André do it
while we were gone.
Is that us... with wings?
We're floating above her.
Always there to protect her.
That's reassuring. Right, Lily? Yes.
We tore you away from everything
you know, but things are normal.
Your fathers are floating fairies.
Can you call André, have him
paint something a little less... gay?
By the way, we need to stop having
friends with names like "André."
Redheaded daddy is angry daddy.
You are. Even Pepper pointed it
out on the way home from the airport.
And that's another one. "Pepper."
Okay, what's up?
All right, look,
I never told my family
we were adopting a baby.
- And...
- I know.
You do?
Yeah, and I don't blame you.
I know your family.
You'd tell them,
they'd say something judgmental.
- Exactly.
- You'd get mad.
Then something supposed to be nothing
but joyful turns into this huge fight.
And who wants a big,
emotional scene like that?
I'm so relieved you understand.
I invited them over
for dinner tonight.
- What?
- I had to.
This would have gone on forever.
You're an avoider.
- I'm calling them and canceling.
- No, you're not.
You're telling your family
you adopted a baby tonight.
And you do have avoidance issues.
Even Longinus said so.
Are you really
not hearing these names?
Don't answer it!
I'll get it!
Hi. Hey. You must be Dylan.
I'm Haley's mother.
Come on. Let's go.
Hang on one second.
You're still in high school?
- Yeah, I'm a senior.
- A senior. Cool.
Phil? Sweetie? Honey?
He is Dylan, and he is a senior.
And you need to scare him.
Lemme meet this playa.
Phil Dunphy, yo.
It's like that. You just stare down
on them. Let the eyes do the work.
Your mouth might be saying, "We cool,"
but your eyes are like, "No, we not."
"Nice to meet you."
"No, it's not."
"S'all good."
"S'no, it s'nisn't."
- Okay, I see you two guys...
- Wait, wait, wait.
You two...
You two keep it real.
Know what I mean, son?
Not really.
- Please stop.
- That's cool.
Oh, God! That's my back!
- Sweetheart...
- I slipped in the baby oil!
"Where are you from originally?"
"I could defeat you if it came
to a physical confrontation."
I don't know about this...
Should I call a doctor?
You're very strong, homes.
Okay, nice.
Nice soft landing.
- Okay, let's go.
- I am on my side, though.
So just flip me right back,
and we're good. We'll be good.
I need to get flipped right on my back,
and we should be fine, so...
Brenda Feldman.
What is that?
- A poem written for Brenda Feldman.
- Of course it is.
I put my thoughts into words,
and now my words into action!
I'll give you 50 bucks
not to do this.
I'm 11 years old.
What am I gonna do with money?
What are you gonna do
with a 16-year-old?
He's like a bullfighter.
Ever see a bullfight?
I can't watch this.
You're in such a bad mood.
And I know why.
It's because that man
thought you were my father.
When you say "no" like that,
it's always "yes."
Come on, we're in the mall.
Let's get you some younger clothes.
- There's a store there that I know...
- I don't need any "younger clothes."
And I don't care what some jackass in
a pair of ripped jeans thinks about me.
Good. You shouldn't.
You should only care what I think.
I love you, and I don't care
how old you are.
So stop being a gloomy goose,
and stop being so hard on Manny.
I'm hard on Manny just because I don't
want to see him make a fool of himself.
And I can smell
that hair goo of his from here.
Look, I don't know what's gonna
happen to him over there,
but you're his family now,
and that means only one thing.
You be the wind in his back,
not the spit in his face.
What?
Something mom always says.
It's gorgeous in Spanish.
He's there.
She has a boyfriend.
I am sorry, mi niño!
I gave her my heart,
and she gave me a picture of me
as an old-time sheriff.
That was pretty stupid of me,
wasn't it?
No, mi amor. It was brave.
Right, Jay? Brave.
Well, you'll know better next time.
Come on, let's get a pretzel.
Excuse me, sir. We ask
that all mall walkers stay to the right.
Alex! Get out!
- Mom!
- Alex, leave your sister alone!
I was just getting my book. Gosh.
I know, sweetie, but you need
to respect their privacy.
What are they doing up there?
Nothing. Lying in her bed,
watching a movie.
I'm making a cake for tonight.
You want to help me
with the frosting?
Sure.
So, you know, if Haley got pregnant,
would you ever pretend
she has mono for a few months
and then,
tell everyone the baby's yours?
What?
This senior at school was
out sick for like four months,
but Jenna Resnick swears she saw her
breast-feeding at a coin-op car wash.
Buddy, what are you wearing?
Nothing.
No jacket. One hat.
How many pairs of underwear
do you have on?
One.
Six.
First of all, it would be really
cool to see Haley that fat,
and how awesome would it be to have
a fake brother who's really my nephew?
Haley is not getting pregnant.
I'm just saying "if."
You like making trouble for your sister,
but it's not gonna work this time.
You know why?
'Cause your sister's a good girl.
I know. I was just like her
when I was...
I want you to know,
I'm not enjoying this,
but this is an important lesson
that you're learning.
Soak it. Keep it...
You're too close.
It's gonna hurt.
It's supposed to hurt.
And why are you smiling?
I'm... what?
Oh, forget it.
I can't do this.
The point is, you're scared.
I think you've learned your lesson...
Mom?!
What are you doing?
I was just, um, dropping off
some laundry. Is this a bad time?
Can you shut the door, please?
Actually,
we're just gonna leave that open.
Why?
Because I have seen
this little show before...
Lying on the bed with a tall senior.
One minute, you're friends watching
"Falcon Crest,"
the next, you're lying underneath
the table, your bra in your pocket.
Mom!
- You hit my bone!
- It was an accident!
- I thought you were my friend!
- I am your friend!
Dad? You have got to talk to mom!
She is, like, completely freaking out
and embarrassing me!
Honey, your mom isn't
always as cool about things...
What is with this thing?!
My dad still isn't
completely comfortable with...
This.
It's been five years now,
and he still does this thing
where he announces himself
before walking into any room we're in,
just to make sure he doesn't
have to ever see us kiss.
Wish my mother had that system.
- Remember?
- Not now.
I still can't believe
you did this to me.
Would you get in the spirit
of things?
It's a celebration.
Oh, God.
I'm gonna go get Lily ready...
and I want you to just
come straight out with it.
You can do this.
Sports-guy chest bump.
Do it. Go.
How are you?
- Hey, guys.
- Hey, here you go.
- Thank you.
- Oh, don't thank us. Open it.
Dad is coming right behind.
We're here! Coming in!
Don't worry, Dad.
Nothing gay going on here.
May I take your multicolored
coat and bejeweled cap?
- What a beautiful dress.
- Ay, thank you, "Feel."
That's how she says "Phil."
Not "Feel", "Phil."
- So, how was your trip?
- It was good, actually.
About that,
I have something
that I need to tell you guys.
We didn't just go to Vietnam
for pleasure.
We kind of have some big news.
Oh, God. If Cam comes out here
with boobs, I'm leaving.
I hope he didn't embarrass you, Mom.
Don't mind her. Haley had
her first boy over today, and...
Phil shot him.
Anyway, so, about a year ago,
Cam and I were sort of
feeling this longing,
for something more,
like a... maybe a baby.
That's a bad idea.
- What do you mean, "bad idea"?
- Kids need a mother.
- If you two guys are bored, get a dog.
- We're not bored, Dad.
I support you, Mitchell,
even though you're not my son.
What dad is trying to say is that,
Mitchell, you're a little uptight,
kids bring chaos,
and you don't handle it well.
That's not what dad's saying.
That's what you're saying.
And it's insulting
in a whole different way.
People, let's all chillax.
Where's Uncle Cameron?
Someone who's not insulting me
notices he's not here.
So that's the big announcement, huh?
You two broke up.
Well, a baby wasn't
gonna help that, anyway.
Let me tell you, you're better off,
because he was a bit of a drama queen.
Stop, stop.
You come into my house
and you insult me and my boyfriend,
who, by the way,
is not that dramatic, and... Oh, God.
We adopted a baby.
Her name is Lily.
Exciting!
Just turn it off.
I can't turn it off. It's who I am.
- The music!
- Yes, the music.
Come say hi to Lily!
A little princess!
She is a little princess!
She is so cute!
Let me see her.
"Lily," isn't that gonna be
hard for her to say?
Excuse me.
I know that I said
I thought this was a bad idea.
But...
What do I know?
I mean, it's not like
I wrote the book on fatherhood.
Been trying all my life to get it right.
I'm still screwing up.
- Right, Manny?
- I wrote a song about it in the car.
Of course you did.
Anyway, I'm happy for you.
And you should know that...
I'm not here to spit in your face.
I'm here to... blow at your back.
- I don't understand.
- I don't...
It's supposed to
sound better in Spanish.
That's beautiful. And thank you.
Anyhow, Mitch...
No, Dad, it's...
I got her.
- She wants her grandpa!
- She wants her daddy!
- Do you want to meet grandpa?
- Are you kidding?
She's one of us now.
Let me see the little pot sticker.
You're a cutie, aren't you?
Look at this.
"We're from different worlds,
"Yet we somehow fit together.
"Love is what binds us,
"Through fair or stormy weather.
"I stand before you now
with only one agenda...
"To let you know my heart is yours,
Feldman comma Brenda."
I mean, seriously!
Luke, so far,
hasn't beaten me in basketball.
It's 2-0.
2-0.
- Get that weak stuff out of my kitchen!
- Dad, stop it!
Can you do me a favor and just...
- This is dumb.
- How's the weather down there?
But when the day comes
that he does win...
if/when he beats me,
I'm just gonna be like,
"Well done. Well done."
Just, like, let him...
Just support him in that kind of stuff.
I'd probably want to just go 2 out of 3
and just see what happens there, but...